Today we're going to make this beautiful vegetable flower centerpiece in crudites.
Not only is it a fabulous centerpiece for your table, it is a unique way to serve your vegetable crudites.
The basket is stuffed full of fresh vegetable sticks ready for dipping.
And the flowers are made of an assortment of root vegetables.
All edible.
Including sweet potatoes, turnip, radish and kohlrabi.
We'll start by preparing some carrot rounds.
You want to peel some carrots up.
You want to use some skinny ones and some fat ones.
So we'll peel those and then we're going to cut a whole bunch of little rounds that we'll use for making our flowers.
So you'll want to cut off the ends.
And then you want to cut a slice.
About a quarter inch slice like that.
Into little rounds.
You want quite a few of these because you need two for each flower.
And it depends on how many flowers you want to make.
If you want a nice full basket of flowers, you're going to make a lot of flowers.
And then you just set those aside.
And then I'll show you how to slice the root vegetables for the flower petals.